The story of a gambling man and a hustling lady and the
empire they fashioned from the wilderness.
McCabe & Mrs. Miller is a western, drama film directed by Robert Altman.
A gambler and a prostitute become thriving business partners in a remote Old
West mining town until a large corporation arrives on the scene.
John McCabe, played by Warren Beatty.
Constance Miller, played by Julie Christie.
Sheehan, played by René Auberjonois.
The Lawyer, played by William Devane.
Smalley, played by John Schuck.
Mr. Elliot, played by Corey Fischer.
McCabe & Mrs.
Miller is a 1971 American revisionist Western film directed by Robert
Altman and starring Warren Beatty and Julie Christie.
The screenplay by Altman and Brian McKay is based on the
1959 novel McCabe by Edmund Naughton.
Set in Washington State during the early 1900s, the film follows a mysterious gambler and alleged shootist (Beatty) who
recruits a British madam (Christie) to run a boomtown brothel, later running afoul of powerful business interests.
Altman referred to it as an "anti-Western" film because it
ignores or subverts a number of Western conventions.
The film is also noted for its cinematography by Vilmos Zsigmond, and its
soundtrack, which features several songs by Leonard Cohen.
Filming took place in British Columbia, Canada in the fall and winter
of 1970, and the film was released by Warner Bros.
on June 24, 1971.
McCabe & Mrs.
Miller has received critical acclaim in the years since its release and earned
an Oscar nomination for Christie in the Best Actress category.
The film was deemed the 8th greatest Western of all time by the American Film Institute in its AFI's 10 Top 10 list in 2008 and, in 2010, was selected for
preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
brothel, snow, gambler, mining town.
The tone is emotional.